http://www.awi.de/en/kontaktseiten/privacy-protection.html

Privacy protection - AWI
FocusOcean Acidification"We are talking about a deadly trio"Ocean acidification – The evil twin of climate warmingFacts on Ocean Acidification"Ocean acidification is the evil little brother of global warming"Success story of a resistance fighterTracing ocean acidificationA view inside – A fish in NMRSwimming in acidic waterSea iceThe most productive algae in the ArcticSea-ice photo galleriesIn the Arctic Sea Ice's KindergartenRemote SensingLife in and underneath sea iceInfograph sea ice researchPermafrostThe signs of changePermafrost - An introductionTanDEM-X satellite image - Changes in permafrost landscapesThe Atlantis of the ArcticHow thick is the old ground iceResearch at the furthest reaches of civilizationA symbolic tree in the Russian ArcticThe Direct Line to the Arctic PermafrostMarine LitterLitterbaseUsing Expertise to Combat Marine Litterlitter in the ocean depthsTracking down microplastic“The Litter is a Whole New Dimension”10 Questions, 10 AnswersQuestion 1Question 2Question 3Question 4Question 5Question 6Question 7Question 8Question 9Question 10Marine Litter-InfographicNorth SeaSeegrass in the Wadden SeaTaking a stroll through the underwater woodsInfographic Invasive SpeciesFood source and treasure troveArctic OceanOceanographic measurements at the 79°North GlacierTiny algae, hugely resilientPolar PredictionsSix questions we always wanted to ask a climate modelerInterviewIce SheetsInfographics Filchner Ronne Ice ShelfHot-Water DrillingE-mails from the Filchner Ice ShelfNew Ice RadarIce really is a hot commodityGreenland's Ice Conveyor BeltMOSAiC ExpeditionWelcome back PolarsternInterview WunderlichInterview with Markus RexThe Expedition in NumbersFactsheet SustainabiltyMOSAiC CountdownInfographic PolarsternIPCC Special Report on the Ocean and Ice – a previewExpeditionShipsPolarsternThe symbol of german polar researchInterview with a capitain of the PolarsternChronicleWeekly Reports PolarsternArchive of Weekly Reports from RV PolarsternHeinckeUthörnMya IIMore ShipsStationsNeumayer Station IIIWorking and living in AntarcticaGeorg von NeumayerConstruction of Neumayer Station IIIWebcamLibrary in the IceAWIPEV Arctic Research Basethe Koldewey Aerosol Raman LidarKohnen StationIsland SamoylovDallmann LaboratoryDrescher Ice CampAircraftPolar 5 + 6LaboratoriesIce Core LaboratoriesProxy LaboratoryNMR laboratoryC-14 labObservatoriesOcean: FRAMFRAM-Geraete enWater: CosynaAir: MeteorologyOn land: GeophysicsCentre for Scientific DivingInfo for
expeditionsInformation SystemsCruise
PlanningWork + StudyAWI as an employerReasons to join AWICareer and prospectsPostdocsApprenticesAdministration and infrastructureOur staffWork-life balanceReconciliation of work and careFlexible childcareThe holiday programmeCrechéEqual OpportunitiesInternational Staff and GuestsLife around AWIList/SyltHelgolandPotsdamBremerhavenInformation on employmentComplaint OfficeHolidayWorking hoursPayPostdocsYoung Investigator GroupsCareer and prospectsResearch supportPROCEED Postdoc OfficeOut of universityAs PhD studentPhD RepresentativesFor graduate thesesAs traineeAs student assistantAs university lecturerAs scholarApprenticeVocational training professionsBiology lab assistantChemistry lab assistantClerk for office managementIT system integration specialistIT application development specialistMedia and information services specialistIndustrial mechanic (Bremerhaven and Helgoland)Plant mechanic for sanitary, heating and air conditioning systemsCareer and PerspectivesAwardsHow to applyOut of schoolas TraineeFuture Dayas VolunteerGeneral informationOur FÖJ Positionsas HIGHSEA ScholarHS TeachersHS ScientistsHS AdmissionHS Admission Procedure - School ReportHS Admission Procedure - Interviewas TeacherOPENSEA HelgolandJobsJob OfferInspiresHow to applyAbout UsOrganisationProfileMission StatementOrganisation chartOrganisation Chart Staff UnitsLegal DepartmentManagementBoard of GovernorsScientific CouncilScientific Advisory BoardLogin Scientific Advisory BoardStaff UnitsContact persons at AWICommunications and Media RelationsPurchasingNational and international officesCooperationsFriends of the AWISustainabilityCO2 Compensation for Business TravelHealth at the WorkplaceSustainable Ship OperationAWI Sustainability GuidelineAlfred Wegener40 years of AWISitesBremerhavenSiteExpedition historyInstitute ManagementPotsdamSitePermafrost ResearchAtmospheric PhysicsPolar Terrestrial Environmental SystemsHelgolandGuest ResearchCoastal Summer School 2019Individual guest scientist staysNewsUniversity CoursesCentre of Excellence NF-POGOSoNoATPOGO SCHOLARS 2016POGO SCHOLARS 2019POGO SCHOLARS 2017POGO SCHOLARS 2018POGO SCHOLARS 2019POGO SCHOLARS 2020submissionServiceCentre for Scientific DivingShipping of BiotaBuildingsSyltWadden Sea StationConference RoomsList Oyster TrailTeamGuest housesGuest Research and CoursesVisiting ScientistsEventsGuided ToursOldenburgLogisticsSchedulesProposalsAdvisory Board NeumayerAdvisory board members polar aircraftInformation for Expedition ParticipantsExpedition Interface System - EISFreight handlingCustomsPort WarehouseServiceContactEventsEvent ManagementArt and ScienceEvent HighlightsCooperationGuided ToursMedia centrePressArchiveBlogs of Alfred Wegener InstitutResearch SupportComputing CentreData Flow FrameworkServices for guests and visitorsData +
ProductsLibraryAWI Journal SubscriptionsArchive for German Polar ResearchGuide to HoldingsArchive Related PublicationsIntroductory LiteratureLinksPublicationsScientific publicationsScientific DataBrochures and ReportsInfographicsReports on Polar and Marine ResearchFurther particulars for the compilation of the reportsOther expeditions, abstracts, proceedingsDissertationsCumulative DissertationTransferTechnology transferKnowledge TransferArctic OfficeClimate OfficeNorth Sea OfficeIPCC OfficeEU-PolarNetMain FocusInternational Integration and Policy GuidancePolar research for science and societyInfrastructure, Facilities and DataInteraction with stakeholdersPartnerNewsEarth System Knowledge PlatformScienceBiosciencesBentho-Pelagic ProcessesMain Research FocusTeamToolsProjectsTeachingCommunicationFunctional EcologyMain Research FocusEcosystem FunctionsAntarcticArcticNorth SeaEvolutionary EcologyDynAMo EnglCoastCarb EnglCrab LabRocky Shore EcologySpecies InteractionsInfluence of global warmingMarine LitterTeamTeaching & OutreachIntegrative EcophysiologyMain Research FocusBiophysics (NMR)Molecular physiologyCellphysiologyIonregulationTeamMarine BiogeoscienceMain Research FocusPhytoplankton EcophysiologyPhytochangeProxy DevelopmentGeochemical AnalysesBiomineralizationBenthic ForaminifersMathematical modellingModelling and feedbacks of biogeochemical cyclesHGF Young Investigator Group MarESysTeamTeaching&OutreachToolsCulturing facilities and laboratoriesLaboratory EquipmentProxy LaboratoryICP-MS facilityEventsCoastal EcologyWorking GroupsWG Coastal GeologyAMINSTENCILSASHAHANSHOWIMCOASTLABSPaleoElbePESOWG Ecosystem AnalysisWG Long-term EcologyResearch topicsWG Community & Evolutionary EcologyTeamResearch highlight: Evolutionary EcologyResearch Highlight: Community EcologyTeamWadden Sea StationVisiting ScientistsEventsWorkshopsFood web models in politics and managementCoursesFood Web Analysis - From sample to modelProjectsShelf Sea System EcologyMain Research FocusEuropean oysterRESTOREPROCEEDOMAPNORATeamDownloadsMarine AquacultureMicro plasticCOSYNAUnderwater Node HelgolandUnderwater node SpitsbergenWorking GroupsMarine AquacultureIn situ EcologyMicrobial EcologyMethanePathogenesMicroplasticsSpring Algal BloomsFood WebLong-term observations (LTO)Helgoland Roads Co-operationsLTER NEWS@HELGOLAND ROADSHelgoland Roads PhytoplanktonHelgoland Roads ZooplanktonEcological restorationTeamAbout HelgolandAbout HelgolandTeachingsEcological ChemistryMain Research FociChemical Ecology of Marine ProtistsPhycotoxinsPlankton EcologyEco-evolutionary Genomics & Molecular EcologyMarine ChemistryTeamResearchEducationToolsSecondary Metabolites and Cellular SignalingECOTRACEModelling on cellular levelTeamExpeditionsProjectsToolsUMEPolar Biological OceanographyMain Research FocusHustedt Diatom Study Centre50 years Hustedt CollectionDiatom collectionDatabaseResearchSHERPAFriedrich HustedtSea ice ecology and sea ice biogeochemistryMolecular Sea Ice EcologyISE-G 2018 enEcophysiology of pelagic key speciesScientific ApproachImplementationProjectsTeamJobsArctic ZooplanktonMolecular Biodiversity of Eukaryotic MicrobesTechnologyScientific approachProjectsTeamArctic plankton ecology and related sedimentary fluxPEBCAOParticle dynamicsTeamTeaching&OutreachDeep-Sea Ecology and TechnologyTeamResearchFood for the deep seaMicrobial communities in the deep seaABYSSHigher life at the deep seafloorExperimental work at the deep seafloorProjects / CooperationsEU-ProjekteHGF-ProjectsESFRI ProjectsBMBF ProjectsFurther ProjectsTechnologyBiogeochemical SensorsPressure tankFoto/Video SystemsFlying DronesFree-falling SystemsMobile pelagic SystemsAutonomous Underwater Vehicle SARIMobile benthic SystemsAutonomous Crawler NOMADSediment SamplersMooringsWater SamplerObservatoriesLTER Observatory HAUSGARTENFRAM Ocean Observing SystemPublicationsDataGeosciencesGeophysicsResearch FocusTransition from Cretaceous Greenhouse to Tertiary IcehouseDevelopment and dynamics of ice sheetsWest Antarctic Ice SheetGreenland WestGreenland EastAnt_PeninsulaNorth Atlantic Deepwater and its precursorsObservatories, long-term measurementsSeismologyGeomagneticsInfrasoundFormation of the Arctic BasinUltraslow spreading mid-ocean ridgesGateways of the Southern OceanLarge Igneous ProvincesBathymetric CompilationsTeamMethods and ToolsBathymetryMultibeamHigh-resolution seismicsSediment echosounderReflection seismologyStreamerRefraction seismologySeismic SourcesPassive SeismologySeismology in subpolar oceansSeismology on drifting sea iceOcean-bottom seismometerDEPASApplicationTechnologyCostsScheduleProjectsPublicationsSeismic land stationsGravity SurveyingGravimetersMagnetic surveyingMagnetometersPhysical propertiesMSCLExpeditionsGlaciologyMain Research FocusField GlaciologyMass balance studiesIce Core DrillingMicrostructure of IcePaleoclimate ResearchIce Sheet ModellingRemote sensingToolsIceCTIce core laboratoriesFabric AnalyserRemote SensingMicrostructure MappingNumerical ModellingRadarRaman SpectroscopySeismicsEducation and TeachingTeamField campaignsProjectsAwardsPermafrost ResearchResearch FocusPermafrost ModellingPermafrost CoastsEnergy and Waterbalancegalleriesnewstest sitesmethodsTeamPermafrost Remote SensingPermafrost BiogeochemistryPermafrost Region Greenhouse GasesSubmarine PermafrostGalleryPermafrost ArchivesPermafrost OutreachPermafrost ChangeFrozen-Ground CartoonsTeamTeaching and EducationLabsProjectsCACOONMOSESNunataryukACDPAGE21CarboPermGTN-PLake EConferencesICRSSpast ICRSS ConferencesInternational Symposium 20 Years of Lena ExpeditionsPolar Terrestrial Environmental SystemsResearch FociArctic Lake System DynamicsThesesEarth System DiagnosticsTeamProjects [en]Newest Research HighlightsPast HighlightsPublicationsHigh-latitude BiodiversityHigh-latitude Vegetation ChangePast Climate ChangeStaffLabs and MethodsPaleogenetic LabUV workstationsDNA isolationDNA enrichmentDNA shearingDNA quantity & qualityStable Isotopes LabFinnigan-MAT Delta-S Mass SpectrometerPDZ Europa Scientific 20-20 Mass SpectrometerThermoFisher Delta-V-Advantage Mass SpectrometerPicarro L2120i Cavity RingDown SpectrometerMicropaleontology LabDiatom laboratoryPollen laboratoryMethods for Arctic Lake ResearchUWITEC Niederreiter HYBRID 90 mm Piston Coring systemUWITEC 60 mm Piston Coring SystemShort cores and surface samplesYakutia 2016Bykovsky 2017Chukotka 2018Methods for Arctic Vegetation AnalysisRemote Sensing MethodsModel developmentTeaching and EducationProjectsMarine GeochemistryOverarching themesResearch themesParticle fluxesNatural radioactivity and GEOTRACESClimate relevant gasesSolute fluxesBiogeochemical processesAge and origin of sediment componentsValidation and application of paleoenvironmental proxiesOrganic proxiesDevelopment of in situ sampling and analytical equipmentEarly diagenetic overprintTeamToolsEquipmentSampling equipmentSediment trapsuspended particlesMethodspore water sampling with rhizonsExpeditionsMICADASTechnologyEA - Elemenal analyzerAGECHSGISVacuum linePFCSample processingProjectsMarine GeologyMain Research FocusTeamToolsProjectsTeaching & EducationPublicationsClimate SciencesClimate DynamicsResearchMethodsProjectsEducationOutreachTeamPolar MeteorologyMain Research FocusBoundary layer processesModellingMethaneLong term observatoryPolarstern MeteorologyWRMC - BSRNEarth Observing SystemsCampaignsACLOUD/AFLUXCampaignsSTABLEAirMethJASPER 2010MELTEX-IMELTEX-IISASKOSTeamPaleoclimate DynamicsResearch FocusToolsProjectsPublicationsTeaching&OutreachTeamHeinrich AwardAtmospheric PhysicsClimate ModellingAerosols & CloudsAtmospheric ChemistryProjects@AWIPEV(AC)3CliC Arctic CORDEXMOSAiCQUARCCSAwardPOLEXStratoClimREKLIMPhysical OceanographyMain Research FocusCirculation in the Arctic Ocean and the Nordic SeasPhysikalische Ozeanographie des arktischen OzeansSouthern Ocean - Overturning CirculationThe southern ocean - circulationOcean-Ice Shelf InteractionOzean-Schelfeis WechselwirkungOcean Acoustics GroupOutreach ActivitiesAWI - Ocean Acoustics Group - Acoustic EcologyAWI - Ocean Acoustics Group - Infrared Based Whale DetectionAWI - Ocean Acoustics Group - Habitat ModelingAWI - Ocean Acoustics Group - Underwater SoundscapesAWI - Ocean Acoustics Group - TeamAWI - Ocean Acoustics Group - Passive Acoustic MonitoringAWI - Ocean Acoustics Group - PublicationsOcean OpticsResearch TopicsProjectsPublicationsCooperation PartnersTeamTeamProjectsMIDORACEARCGATEFISPUDASHFRAMPhytoopticsInstrumentsCTD Instrument and Water SamplerTransportable Helicopter - CTDTransportable Helicopter - CTDFloatsOceanography mooring systemsIce-Tethered ProfilerTiefsee YoyoDetaillierte BeschreibungBildserie zum Aussetzen der Jojo-VerankerungUnderwater winchPerformance reportPrecision Salinometer SystemMeasurement PrincipleLong Term ObservationsLongterm Observation AntarcticTechnology and LogisticsResultsDataExpeditionsPublicationsLong-Term Observations ArcticFram StraitCentral ArcticObserving systemsTeachingSea Ice PhysicsMain Research FociSea Ice Thickness - Mass BalanceEngergy BudgetsAlbedoTransmissionRecent ResultsIce Ocean DynamicsSnow on Sea IceTechnology DevelopmentRemote SensingMerged Analysis and ForecastingFreshwater fluxesForecast of sea ice propertiesIICWG-DATeamToolsAircraft based observationsVessel based observationsRemote SensingModell SimulationsAutonomous PlatformsVessels / Ice StationsEarth System ModelsData AssimilationProjectsIce BirdAFIN: Antarctic Fast Ice NetworkESA Climate Change InitiativeIceArc: Arctic Ice Climate and EconomicsMOSAiCSPICESTransdrift: Arctic Ice-Ocean-InteractionChanging Arctic OceanArctic AmplificationJunior GroupsCOPERECOTRACEResearchInorganics in organicsIron limitation and cyclingGrazers impact on Fe biogeochemistryPhytoplankton community dynamicsBeyond iron: vitamins, zinc and cobaltFe-Mn LimitationLaboratoryExpeditionsProjectsCooperationsECUSTeamLatest ResearchFluxWINIcefluxPublicationsTeamMarESysTeamModelsGCB OceanThe effect of deformation mechanisms for ice sheet dynamicsPALICEPublicationsInternational CooperationsMethodsWorking areasPeta-CarbTeamResultsCarbonRemote SensingExpeditionsSamoylov-April-2018Alaska-2018-07Alaska-2017-07Lena-Delta-September-2017Lena-Delta-August-2018Central-Alaska-2017-03SoboSiseBykovsky-2016-08Bykovsky-April-2017Alaska-2016-08ICOP 2016SoboSiseBykovsky-2015-08Alaska-2015-07Alaska-2014-04Alaska-2014-08Central-Yakutia-2015-03SoboSiseBykovsky-2014-08NewsPETA-CARB in the MediaCooperationsSEAPUMPTeamResearchCarbon exportAggregate ProcessesZooplankton grazing on aggregatesShip CruisesPlanktoSERVProject StructureAnalytical TechniquesJob OffersPublicationsSSIPSPACETeamPermaRiskNewsModellingRemote SensingIce RoadsSpecial GroupsScientific ComputingData AssimilationPDAF - Parallel Data Assimilation FrameworkData Assimilation PublicationsBioinformaticsSoftwarePhyloGenaPublications of AWI Bioinformatics GroupUser supportHigh-Performance ComputingBremHLRComputers/HardwareDKRZTsunamiScientific DivingNews from the CSDCourse ReportsLocations and FacilitiesWho can Dive at the AWI?Scientific ProjectsPublicationsMarGateBiota orderThe use of small boatsLicence refreshmentScientific DiverSupervisor for Scientific DiverProject support (Guests & Partners)Special coursesMembers of the working groupContactBionicsFields of ResearchApplied ResearchBasic ResearchContract Research / Industrial ProjectsTeamProjectsRobustnessGood VibrationsOASISMorphogenesisSensor E-PlusMaterial ResearchEducation & CommunicationEducationCommunicationPublicationsToolsPlancton-LabBionicsMicroscopyBionicsAdditive Manufacturing (3D-printing)Computer Aided Engineering (CAE)ELISEStrategy & HistoryAquacultureAquaculture ResearchProjectsInEValMedSponsalmon lousePhycoFarmingAquaVitaeID3ASStudentsExtrClimAquaGrade AidAkPhaKolOFFoMVGamFoodN-out of AquacultureTRUECAMAFANRecAlSONAQUAMaNaKaIDeAFiTUvPaaCompleted ProjectsTeamCentre for Aquaculture Research (ZAF)TopicsRAS TechnologySustainable NutritionInvertebratesIntegrated Multi-Trophic AquacultureMicroalgaeImpactPublicationsPoster / PresentationPressTeachingEventsPartnerMarine AquacultureKey topicsOffshore aquacultureCandidate speciesIMTARecirculation aquaculture systemsSocial Dimension of AquacultureTeamResearchGAINEnviSim4MareMak-PakCo-UseMUSESBAQUANeuseeland Muschel AquakulturBioDivBlueChangeOceanGovOPP COST-ActionSelected finished projectsEducationInfrastructureArctic OfficeREKLIMClimate Officeseaiceportal.deGateway to the ArcticMaritimes Zentrum ElbinselnKlimastadt BremerhavenClimateXperienceCompetition short storiesExhibition St. Stephani, BremenStage play ColeopteraExhibition Europaschule UtbremenMiscellaneous projects and activitiesInternship at the climate office for polar regions and sea level riseNorth Sea OfficeResearch Highlight: Community EcologyResearch highlight: Evolutionary EcologyTeamESKP English versionResearch
infrastructureResearch
ProgramResearch Unit 1aResearch Unit 2Research Unit 3Research Unit 4Research Unit 5Long Term ObservationsNEWS ArchiveLTO EventsIOC-UNESCO Trends PO workshopsymposium_high_through_put_methodsMolecular methodsGlobal time series resourcesAbstractsAtmosphereArctic (AWIPEV)Surface MeteorologyLong-term MeteorologySurface RadiationLong-term Observation of Surface RadiationRadiosondesLong-term Upper-Air Meteorologystratospheric water vapourLIDARAntarctic (Neumayer)MeteorologyMet-Lab Photo GalleryNo easy job... (series of pictures)Backscatter profilesOzoneAir ChemistryTechnical aspectsScientific programResultsAutomatic aerosol sampling at KohnenPolarsternSynoptic ObservationsCodeUpper Air SoundingscontinuousSensorsCeilometerAutomatic Weather StationsSøråsenFilchnerBiologyNorth SeaArcticAntarctic BiologyData +
ProductsKnowledge TransferTechnology TransferTechnology PortalSoftwareTechnology Transfer - Offers to the private sectorAWI Patent for kill-free caviar productionTechnology Transfer - From Research to commercial ApplicationCommercialisation Pathwaysspin-offsThe Technology Transfer OfficeTTO TeamAwards and honoursGood Scientific PracticeImprintContactTwitter Facebook
deEnglish
Alfred-Wegener-InstitutHelmholtz-Zentrum für Polar-und Meeresforschung
JobsMediaMultimediaContactImprintData ProtectionDeutschEnglish
HomeFocusOcean AcidificationSea icePermafrostMarine LitterNorth SeaArctic OceanPolar PredictionsIce SheetsMOSAiC ExpeditionIPCC Special Report on the Ocean and Ice – a previewExpeditionShipsPolarsternHeinckeUthörnMya IIMore ShipsStationsNeumayer Station IIIAWIPEV Arctic Research BaseKohnen StationIsland SamoylovDallmann LaboratoryDrescher Ice CampAircraftPolar 5 + 6LaboratoriesIce Core LaboratoriesProxy LaboratoryNMR laboratoryC-14 labObservatoriesOcean: FRAMWater: CosynaAir: MeteorologyOn land: GeophysicsCentre for Scientific DivingInfo forexpeditionsInformation SystemsCruisePlanningWork + StudyAWI as an employerReasons to join AWICareer and prospectsOur staffWork-life balanceEqual OpportunitiesInternational Staff and GuestsLife around AWIInformation on employmentPostdocsYoung Investigator GroupsCareer and prospectsResearch supportPROCEED Postdoc OfficeOut of universityAs PhD studentFor graduate thesesAs traineeAs student assistantAs university lecturerAs scholarApprenticeVocational training professionsCareer and PerspectivesAwardsHow to applyOut of schoolas TraineeFuture Dayas Volunteeras HIGHSEA Scholaras TeacherJobsJob OfferHow to applyAbout UsOrganisationProfileOrganisation chartManagementStaff UnitsContact persons at AWIPurchasingNational and international officesCooperationsFriends of the AWISustainabilityAlfred Wegener40 years of AWISitesBremerhavenPotsdamHelgolandSyltOldenburgLogisticsSchedulesProposalsInformation for Expedition ParticipantsFreight handlingServiceContactEventsMedia centrePressResearch SupportComputing CentreLibraryArchive for German Polar ResearchPublicationsScientific publicationsScientific DataBrochures and ReportsInfographicsReports on Polar and Marine ResearchTransferTechnology transferKnowledge TransferArctic OfficeClimate OfficeNorth Sea OfficeIPCC OfficeEU-PolarNetEarth System Knowledge PlatformScienceBiosciencesBentho-Pelagic ProcessesFunctional EcologyIntegrative EcophysiologyMarine BiogeoscienceCoastal EcologyShelf Sea System EcologyEcological ChemistryPolar Biological OceanographyDeep-Sea Ecology and TechnologyGeosciencesGeophysicsGlaciologyPermafrost ResearchPolar Terrestrial Environmental SystemsMarine GeochemistryMarine GeologyClimate SciencesClimate DynamicsPolar MeteorologyPaleoclimate DynamicsAtmospheric PhysicsPhysical OceanographySea Ice PhysicsJunior GroupsCOPERECOTRACEECUSFluxWINIcefluxMarESysThe effect of deformation mechanisms for ice sheet dynamicsPALICEPeta-CarbSEAPUMPPlanktoSERVSSIPSPACEPermaRiskSpecial GroupsScientific ComputingScientific DivingBionicsAquacultureArctic OfficeREKLIMClimate OfficeNorth Sea OfficeESKP English versionResearchinfrastructureResearch ProgramResearch Unit 1aResearch Unit 2Research Unit 3Research Unit 4Research Unit 5Long Term ObservationsNEWS ArchiveLTO EventsAtmosphereBiologyData + ProductsKnowledge TransferTechnology TransferTechnology PortalTechnology Transfer - Offers to the private sectorTechnology Transfer - From Research to commercial ApplicationThe Technology Transfer OfficeTTO TeamAwards and honoursGood Scientific Practice
Home// Privacy protection
Privacy Notice
Dear visitors to the Internet portal of Alfred-Wegener-Institut Helmholtz-Zentrum für Polar- und Meeresforschung. To ensure that you feel secure when visiting our website, we would like to inform you below about how we handle your data. We neither publish your data nor pass it on to third parties without your consent. Below we explain what types of data we collect when you visit our web pages and precisely how it is used:
A.  General information
1.  Extent of data processing
We only process personal data collected from our users insofar as this is necessary for the provision of a functional web presence and our content and services. As a rule, personal data provided by our users is only processed with their consent. One exception is where statutory regulations permit the processing of data.
2.  Legal basis for data processing
Art. 6 (1)(a) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) serves as the legal basis whenever we obtain the consent of the person concerned ("data subject") for the processing of their personal data.
Art. 6 (1)(b) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) serves as the legal basis for the processing of personal data which is necessary for performing a contract to which the data subject is a party. The same applies to processing that is required for carrying out pre-contractual measures.
Art. 6 (1)(f) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) serves as the legal basis when processing is necessary to safeguard a legitimate interest of AWI or a third party, and provided this legitimate interest is not outweighed by the data subject’s interests and fundamental rights and freedoms.
3.  Data erasure and storage duration
The personal data of the data subject is erased, anonymised or blocked as soon as the purpose of the storage ceases to apply. In addition, storage may take place if required by European or national law in EU regulations, laws or other regulations to which AWI is subject. Blocking, anonymisation or deletion of the data also takes place if a storage period prescribed by the standards mentioned expires, unless there is a need for further storage of the data in order to conclude or fulfil the contract.
4.  Controller’s contact details
Data controller within the meaning of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and other national data protection legislation as well as any other data protection regulations:
Alfred-Wegener-Institut Helmholtz-Zentrum für Polar-und Meeresforschung Am Handelshafen 12 27570 Bremerhaven
Contact form: https://www.awi.de/ueber-uns/service/kontakt.html
Internet: https://www.awi.de
5.  Contact details of the data protection officer:
The controller's data protection officer is:
Christoph Wagner Tel.: +49 (471) 4831-1637 E-mail: datenschutz(at)awi.de
B.  Provision of the website and creation of log files
We store data relating to individual visits to our website for statistical purposes to improve the quality of our web pages. This data record consists of:the page from which the data file was requested,the name of the data file,the date and time of the query,the quantity of data transmitted, the status of access (the file was transmitted or the file was not found), a description of the type of web browser used,the IP address of the inquiring computer. The data is stored in the log files of our systems. Storage of this data together with other personal data of the user does not take place.
The legal basis for the temporary storage of data and the log files is Art. 6 (1)(f) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Storage in log files is carried out to ensure the functionality of the website. In addition, the data is used to optimise the web pages, to carry out troubleshooting and to ensure the security of our IT systems. These purposes also constitute our legitimate interest in the data processing pursuant to Art. 6 (1)(f) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).
The data is deleted as soon as it is no longer needed to achieve the purpose for which it was collected. In the case of data collection for the provision of the website, the data is deleted when the respective session has ended. If the data is stored in log files, it will be deleted after seven days at the latest. Further storage is possible, in which case the IP addresses are deleted or altered so that identification of the calling client is no longer possible.
The collection of data for the purpose of providing the website and storage of the data in log files is absolutely necessary for the operation of the website. Consequently, there is no right to objection on the part of the user.
C.  Web analysis
We use the web analytics program Matomo (formerly Piwik) for the statistical collection of data on how users utilise our website. It collects various information on your computer with cookies and Javascript and transmits it automatically to us. Each time our website is accessed, our system automatically collects the following data and information from the computer system of the accessing computer:IP address, anonymised through abbreviationTwo cookies for distinguishing between different visitors (_pk_id.44.a4d7 and _pk_ses.44.a4d7)Previously visited URL (referrer), if sent from the browserName and version of the operating systemName, version and language setting of the browserIn addition, if JavaScript is activated: Visited URLs on this websiteTimes of page visitsType of HTML enquiriesScreen resolution and colour depthTechnologies and formats supported by the browser (e.g. cookies, Java, Flash, PDF, WindowsMedia, QuickTime, Realplayer, Director, SilverLight, Google Gears)The storage and evaluation of data is carried out solely on a central server operated by AWI. In addition to the central website www.awi.de, it is also used by most project websites assigned to AWI.
The legal basis for the processing of users’ personal data is Art. 6 (1)(f) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Processing the personal data of users enables us to analyse how our users utilise the website. By evaluating the acquired data, we are able to compile information on the use of the individual components of our website. This helps us to continuously improve our website and its user-friendliness. These purposes also constitute our legitimate interest in the data processing pursuant to Art. 6 (1)(f) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). By anonymising the IP address, sufficient consideration is given to the interests of users in protecting their personal data.
The data is erased after formation of the final annual totals for the access statistics.
Of course, you have the option of objecting to the data collection. You have the following independent ways of objecting to data being acquired through the central server:
1. Activate the “do not track” setting in your browser. As long as this setting is active, our central server will not be able to store any of your data. Important: The “do not track” instruction usually only applies to the device and the browser in which you activate the setting. If you use several devices/browsers, you have to activate “do not track” separately everywhere.
2. Use our opt-out function. Click on the tick in the following option box to stop or reactivate data collection. As long as this option box is deactivated, our central server will not be able to store any of your data. Important: For the opt-out, we need to store a special recognition cookie in your browser. If you delete it or utilise a different PC/browser, you will need to revoke data collecting again on this page.
Storage of this data together with other personal data of the user does not take place.
D.  Use of cookies
Our website uses cookies. Cookies are text files stored in the Internet browser or by the Internet browser on the user's computer system. If a user visits a website, a cookie can be stored on the user's operating system. This cookie contains a sequence of characters enabling the browser to be clearly identified when visiting the website again.
We deploy cookies to make our website more user-friendly. Some elements of our website also technically require the identification of the visiting browser after a change of page. The following data is saved and transmitted in the cookies:
·       "_pk_id.44.a4d7" – Piwik (Matomo) ID for tracking.
·       "_pk_ses.44.a4d7" – Piwik (Matomo) session for tracking.
·       "fe_typo_user" – TYPO3 cookie for distinguishing between front end users.
The legal basis for personal data processing using cookies is Art. 6 (1)(f) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). The purpose of using technically necessary cookies is to simplify the utilisation of websites for users. Some of our website's functions cannot be offered without the use of cookies. For these, it is necessary that the browser can also be recognised again following a change of page. We require cookies for the following applications:Transferring the browser's language setting: automatic selection of the homepage and spellcheckRemembering entered form data: search terms used in the website, entries in the contact form (Section E)User data gathered by technically necessary cookies is not utilised to prepare user profiles. These purposes also constitute our legitimate interest in processing personal data, pursuant to Art. 6 (1)(f) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).
Cookies are stored on the user's computer, which transmits them to our site.  For this reason, you, as the user, also have full control over the utilisation of cookies. You can deactivate or restrict the transmission of cookies by changing your Internet browser settings. Cookies that have already been saved can be deleted at any time. This can also be done automatically. If cookies for our website are deactivated, you may find that not all of the website's functions can continue to be utilised in full.
In addition, we use cookies on our website to enable analysis of how users utilise our website. For more information on this topic, please refer to the information provided under C.
E.  Contact form
There is a contact form on our website that can be used to contact us electronically. If you use this option, the data entered voluntarily in the input screen is transmitted to us and stored. This normally comprises your email address, first name and surname. We inform you about the actual processing of data while you are using the form and we obtain your consent. Reference is also made to the privacy notice. The data is used solely for processing the conversation.
The legal basis for processing the data when using the contact form, if the user’s consent has been given, is Art. 6 (1)(a) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Personal data from the input screen is processed solely for the purpose of acting on the contact request. The data is deleted as soon as it is no longer needed to achieve the purpose for which it was collected. This is the case when the relevant conversation with the user has ended or when the user’s request has finally been processed. The conversation has ended when it is apparent from the circumstances that the issue in question has been finally clarified. The user may at any time withdraw their consent to the processing of personal data vis-à-vis the contact persons listed.
Your personal data will only be transmitted to government organisations and authorities if required by law and/or for the purpose of prosecution in the event of attacks on our network infrastructure. Forwarding to third parties for other purposes does not take place.
F.  Rights of the data subject
As the data subject whose personal data is collected within the scope of the above-mentioned services, you have the following rights, unless any legal exceptions apply in individual cases:Information (Art. 15 GDPR)Rectification (Art. 16 GDPR)Erasure (Art. 17 (1) GDPR)Restriction of processing (Art. 18 GDPR)Data portability (Art. 20 GDPR)Objection to processing (Art. 21 GDPR)Withdrawal of consent (Art. 7 (3) GDPR)Right to lodge a complaint with a supervisory authority (Art. 77 GDPR). For AWI, this is the Landesbeauftragte für den Datenschutz und Informationssicherheit (State Data Protection and Freedom of Information Officer), Arndtstrasse 1, 27570 Bremerhaven.G.  Social media
Two clicks for more data protection
In order to protect our users' privacy and data, we use the tried-and-tested two-click process, also known as the Shariff solution, for sharing content in social networks. The use of this process means that our websites are delivered with inactive buttons that do not transfer any data to social networks. Users can nonetheless manually activate the buttons, thereby creating a connection to their preferred network (first click). The second step involves the user then giving their recommendation (second click). Activating one of the buttons in the first step therefore means that the user consents to transmit data to the social network concerned for this one page and for the requested service.
Data protection regulations on the use of Facebook
We have integrated components of Facebook on some of our web pages. Facebook is a social network.
A social network is a social meeting place on the Internet, an online community that generally enables users to communicate with one another and to interact in a virtual space. Among other things, Facebook enables the users of its social network to create private profiles, upload photos and build a network by means of friend requests.
Facebook is operated by Facebook, Inc., 1 Hacker Way, Menlo Park, CA 94025, USA. If you live outside the USA or Canada, the controller for the processing of personal data is Facebook Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Ireland.
Each time you access one of the individual pages of the website operated by us as the controller and on which a Facebook component is integrated, the browser of your IT system is automatically prompted by the Facebook component to download an image of the Facebook component from Facebook. An overview of all Facebook plug-ins can be found at https://developers.facebook.com/docs/plugins/?locale=de_DE. In the course of this technical procedure, Facebook receives information about which specific pages of our website you have visited.
If you are logged into Facebook at the same time, Facebook recognises which specific sub-page of our website you visit every time you access our website, for the entire duration of your visit. This information is collected by the Facebook component and assigned to your Facebook account by Facebook.
Facebook will in each case be notified via the Facebook component that you have visited our website, provided you are simultaneously logged into Facebook when accessing our website; this takes place irrespective of whether you click the Facebook component or not. If you do not agree to such transmission of information to Facebook, you can prevent it by logging out of your Facebook account prior to accessing our website.
Facebook’s data policy, which can be retrieved from https://de-de.facebook.com/about/privacy/, provides information about the collection, processing and use of personal data by Facebook. It also explains the settings Facebook offers to protect your privacy. In addition, a number of applications are available that make it possible to prevent the transfer of data to Facebook. You can use such applications to prevent your data being transferred to Facebook.
Data protection regulations on the use of Twitter
We have integrated components of Twitter on some of our web pages. Twitter is a multilingual, publicly accessible micro-blogging service where users can publish and share so-called tweets, i.e. short messages limited to 280 characters. These short messages can be accessed by anyone, i.e. also by individuals not registered with Twitter. Twitter makes it possible to address a broader audience via hashtags, links or retweets.
Twitter is operated by Twitter, Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA.
Each time you access one of the individual web pages operated by us as the controller and on which a Twitter component is integrated, the browser of your IT system is automatically prompted by the Twitter component to download an image of the Twitter component from Twitter. Please see https://help.twitter.com/de/using-twitter/embed-twitter-feed for more information on the Twitter timeline.
If you are logged into Twitter at the same time, Twitter recognises - with each visit of our website on which the Twitter component is used - which specific sub-page of our website you visit. This information is collected by the Twitter component and assigned to your Twitter account by Twitter.
Twitter will in each case be notified via the Twitter component that you have visited our website, provided you are simultaneously logged into Twitter when accessing our website; this takes place irrespective of whether you click the Twitter component or not. If you do not agree to such transmission of information to Twitter, you can prevent it by logging out of your Twitter account prior to accessing our website.
Please see https://twitter.com/privacy?lang=de for the applicable data privacy policy of Twitter.
Use of external map services
Data protection regulations on the use of Google Maps
Some of our web pages use Google Maps for showing a site layout. Google Maps is operated by Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. By using this website, you consent to the capture, processing and use of the data that is automatically collected, and of the data that you enter, by Google, its agents and external service providers.
You will find our Terms of Use for Google Maps at “Terms of Use for Google Maps”. For full details on the relevant data protection regulations see https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=de.
We also use YouTube for the embedding of videos as well as Adobe Spark (e.g.: https://www.awi.de/im-fokus/eisschilde/schelfeis-abbruch.html) and have incorporated blogs from the Helmholtz blog portal.
Statistical surveys
Last update: 06.09.2018
Alfred-Wegener-InstitutHelmholtz-Zentrum für Polar-und Meeresforschung
FocusOcean AcidificationSea icePermafrostMarine LitterNorth SeaArctic OceanPolar PredictionsIce SheetsMOSAiC ExpeditionIPCC Special Report on the Ocean and Ice – a previewExpeditionResearch Vessel and cutterStationsAircraftLaboratoriesObservatoriesCentre for Scientific DivingInfo for expeditionsInformation SystemsCruise PlanningWork + StudyAWI as an employerPostdocsOut of universityApprenticeOut of schoolJobsAbout UsOrganisationSitesLogisticsServicePublicationsTransferScienceBiosciencesGeosciencesClimate SciencesJunior GroupsSpecial GroupsResearch infrastructureResearch ProgramLong Term ObservationsData | Scientific Products | Information SystemsKnowledge TransferTechnology TransferAwards and honoursGood Scientific PracticeDirect toTechnology TransferArchive of German Polar ResearchLibraryJob offersmedia centreContactImprintPrivacy protectionAccessibilitySitemap© Alfred-Wegener-Institut
